#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/salvador-rojas-murillo-41225a7a (LinkedIn)

# Top Skills

Human Factors
Human Computer Interaction
Research

## Languages

English (Full Professional)
Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

#### **Publications**

Skill Assessment in the Interpretation of 3D Fracture Patterns from Radiographs. Manuscript #:SIH-S-15-00266.

# Salvador Rojas murillo

Assistant Professor at Hofstra University Nassau County

# Summary

Ph.D in Industrial Engineering in human factors and ergonomics.

Profesional experience includes Healthcare University of Iowa Hospitals and Clinics UIHC.

Manufacturing experience as Production Supervisor for Blinds to GO in NJ and Plant Engineer for VFJeanswear (Lee Jeans).

Faculty experience includes teaching at Hofstra University, Monterrey Institute of Higher Education (Mexico), Thomas Jefferson University (Mexico), Vasco University (Mexico), Morelia Institute of Technology (Mexico).

# Experience

Hofstra University
Assistant Professor
August 2017 - Present (5 years 1 month)
Hempstead, New York

The University of Iowa
Teaching Assistant and PhD Student
August 2012 - Present (10 years 1 month)
University of Iowa

Engineering Problem Solving I (EPS I), Manufacturing Systems, Quality Control and Human Factors.

Contributed in the development of course curriculum. In addition, in charge of office hours to provide academic support to students and grading homework assignments, projects, quizzes and exams. Nominated to the best TA award Fall 2014.

university of iowa hospitals and clinics Research Engineer February 2016 - November 2017 (1 year 10 months) Iowa City, Iowa Area Development of simulation models for streamline processes, reduce waiting time and improve patient's satisfaction

## Masco Corporation

Co Op

July 2013 - July 2013 (1 month)

Using arena performed a simulation of a manufacturing cell. identified bottle necks and proposed different improvements based on different simulation scenarios. This project was performed in a very short time period of 3 weeks.

### Universidad Vasco de Quiroga

Head of the departments of Industrial Engineering and Computer Science

August 2007 - August 2011 (4 years 1 month)

Managed the Industrial Engineering Department and the Computer Systems Engineering Department at Vasco University a private University in Morelia Mexico.

In charge of Professor's selection, training and assessment. In addition, in charge of department daily management activities and year planning.

Moreover, I was in charge of promoting academic activities marketing activities to attract new students and student's supervision and guidance.

#### Grupo de Oro

Government Sales Manager

March 2002 - August 2007 (5 years 6 months)

In charge of state governmental sales for a material construction company.

During this program, we sold about 10 million USD a year of cement and other construction materials to different state agencies.

The sale activities involved logistics, taking orders, and finally collection.

#### Blinds To Go

Supervisor

January 2001 - February 2002 (1 year 2 months)

Lakewood, NJ

In charge of the horizontal blinds department. In charge of daily operations for this department, including operator training and supervision, achieving production goals and improving AQL.

Performed several changes to apply Lean methods.

VF Jeanswear

#### Plant Engineer

June 1996 - September 1998 (2 years 4 months)

Tekax, Yucatan Mexico

I was part of the team that started a new manufacturing facility. This plant incorporated personnel with no previous experience in a manufacturing environment. I was in charge of operator training and we were able to start from 0 daily units to 20,000 daily units of basic Jeans.

Served as a liaison between operations in the US and Mexico.

In charge of methods engineering and cost analysis for all operations and styles that run.

Proposed and carried-out several operation improvements such as lay-out modifications, and operator's training methods

## Education

University of Iowa

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Human Factors · (2011 - 2017)

Lehigh University

Master of Engineering (MEng), Industrial Engineering · (1999 - 2000)

Instituto Tecnológico de Morelia

Bachelor of Science (BS), Industrial Engineering (1990 - 1995)

# Activity

08/26/2022, Viewed by Andrés Morales López